[Music]
foreign
the largest study in history on the
health effects of being overweight
analyzing data for more than 50 million
people from nearly 200 countries found
that excess body weight accounts for
their premature deaths
of about 4 million people every year
most of these deaths are from heart
disease but the researchers found
convincing or probable evidence linking
obesity to 20 different disorders a
variable alphabet soup of potential
health concerns in the ABCs of Health
consequences A is for arthritis
obesity can make rheumatoid arthritis
worse and increase the risk of another
inflammatory joint disease these
so-called disease of King's gout the
most common joint disease in the world
though is osteoarthritis and obesity may
be the main modifiable risk factor
osteoarthritis develops when the
cushioning cartilage lining of joints
breaks down faster than your body can
build it back up the knees are the most
commonly affected leading to the
assumption that the relation to obesity
was simply the you know excess wear and
tear from the added load on the joints
but non-weight-bearing joints like the
hands and the wrists can also be
affected suggests the link isn't you
know purely mechanical obesity related
dyslipidemia may be playing a role with
elevations and the amounts of
triglycerides fat and cholesterol in the
blood aggravating inflammation in the
joints just like cholesterol can
aggravate the inflammation in your
artery walls osteoarthritis suffers not
only have higher cholesterol levels in
the blood they have higher cholesterol
levels within their joints both in
aspirated joint fluid and in cartilage
itself
drip cholesterol on human cartilage in a
Petri dish and you can worsen the
inflammatory degeneration helping to
explain why the higher people's
cholesterol the worse their disease
cholesterol lowering statin drugs May
both self-prevent and treat
osteoarthritis as can a
cholesterol-lowering diet I don't think
enough plant-based diet may offer The
Best of Both Worlds dropping cholesterol
as much as a starting dose of a Statin
drug within a single week and only has
good side effects such as lowering blood
pressure and facilitating weight loss
even just losing about a pound a year
over the span of a decade May decrease
the odds of developing osteoarthritis by
more than 50 percent weight reduction
may even obviate the need for knee
replacement surgery obese arthritis
suffers randomized to lose weight
improve their knee function as much as
those going through surgery all within
just eight weeks the researchers
included that losing 20 pounds of fat
might be regarded as an alternative to
knee replacement I mean isn't it easier
to just get your knees replaced and lose
20 pounds you know rarely discuss is the
fact that nearly 1 in 200 knee
replacement patients die within 90 days
of surgery given the extreme popularity
of this operation about 700 thousand a
year in the U.S an Orthopedics journal
editor suggested that people considering
this operation are inadequately attuned
to the possibility it may kill them
arguably the single most Salient fact to
share with a patient considering the
operation an orthopedic surgeon
responded questioning whether patients
should be told about the chance the
operation May kill them quote to me the
real question is whether this knowledge
will help the patient will it add to the
anxiety of the already anxious patient
perhaps to the point of denying that
patient a helpful operation or will this
knowledge motivate a less handicapped
patient to stick to a diet and physical
activity regime ultimately then the
question boils down to the surgeon's
judgment
among the vast majority who survive the
surgery approximately one in five knee
replacement patients describing
unsatisfied with the outcome weight loss
with a healthy diet on the other hand
may offer a non-surgical alternative
that instead treats the cause and offers
only
beneficial side effects
[Music]
thank you